this problem gives us an array of
numbers
and we need to use the array select
method
to iterate over this array of numbers
and
return a new array containing only the
numbers that are divisible by
three we will assign the returned array
to a variable and then print its value
when we want to return a new array
that contains only the elements for
which
some condition evaluates as true
then we can use the array select method
so we'll call select on our numbers
array
and let's call our block parameter
number
and within this block we're going to
place the
condition by which we want each element
of this numbers array evaluated
in this case we want to know whether
each element
is divisible by three
so each element of our numbers array
will be
passed to the block and assigned to the
block parameter number
[Music]
writing our code like this using the
modulus operator
will return the remainder
of dividing number by three
we can actually hop into irb to see this
we know that 12
is evenly divisible by 3.
so let's check their return value
you can see that the remainder of
dividing 12 by 3
is 0. let's choose a number let's say
11 that's not evenly divisible by
3. using the code 11
modulus 3 we can see that the return
value is
2 indicating that 11
is not evenly divisible by 3.
so the comparison that we need to
perform here on line
4 is to compare the return value
of number modulus 3 or in other words
the remainder of number divided by 3
to 0. this comparison will return a
boolean
either true or false if it returns
true the element currently being
referenced by
this block parameter number will be
included
in the new returned array if this
comparison returns
false it will not be included let's
store this new array returned by the
select method
in a variable called divisible by 3.
and we'll use p to output this new array
and you can see that our new array
contains the elements
9 21 and 39
these are the only numbers from our
original array
which are evenly divisible by 3.
so while map performs transformation
based on the return value of its block
select perform selection if the return
value
of its block for a given element is
truthy
then select will place that element in
the new
returned array if the return value
of the block for a particular element is
falsy
then that element will not be included
in the returned array